multivu.com 2017-06-22

# PR Newswire Privacy Policy

PR Newswire is the global leader in news and information distribution services for professional communicators. As used in this Privacy Policy, the terms "PR Newswire", “we” and “us” refer to PR Newswire Association LLC and its divisions and affiliates, including MultiVu, Vintage and Virtual Press Office, Inc.

PR Newswire is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

In this Privacy Policy, we refer to our Websites, and other online products and services collectively as the "Services." The term "Services" also includes any surveys, newsletters, webinars, contests, blogs and promotions that you may subscribe to or participate in through our Websites, and any white papers, articles, infographics, case studies, videos or other content created by or on behalf of PR Newswire that you download.

In addition to information obtained through your use of the Services, this Privacy Policy also applies to information that we obtain when you register for, purchase or otherwise communicate with us about the Services, including by e-mail, telephone and otherwise. Certain of our Services may be available via mobile app. This privacy policy governs the collection and use of data about you and your use of any PR Newswire mobile app. (Although, we may provide additional notice and choice options within the app itself.)

Note to Journalists, Experts and PR Professionals: News and journalism are public activities. Your name, business contact details, and professional interests and affiliations may already be publicly available, particularly if you are a journalist, a recognized expert, or a PR professional. We have created this Privacy Policy because we recognize that, even in a business context, you may have a need and expectation that your identity and interests be kept anonymous or private in certain circumstances. We want to be clear about when and how we protect that expectation.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to understand how we will treat your information before you start to use our Services or communicate with us about them.

By using our services or communicating with us about them, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this privacy policy, including any updates and amendments. if you do not agree to the terms of this privacy policy, you must not access or use our services or communicate with us about them.

Please click on the sections below to learn more about our Privacy Policy:

  * **HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION FROM YOU**
  * **HOW YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE USED**
  * **HOW YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE SHARED**
  * **COOKIES AND BEACONS**
  * **YOUR CHOICES**
  * **CHILDREN**
  * **LINKS TO THIRD PARTY SITES**
  * **CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**
  * **CONTACT**

_**How We Collect Information from You**_

**Information You Provide to Us**

We collect information that you provide directly to us, including when you register for or order a Service, when a company, organization or individual authorizes you to manage its account or use our Services on its behalf, and/or when you subscribe to a newsletter, provide feedback about our Services or contact us with questions or comments about a Service.

We will not ask for or request sensitive information such as government identifiers, medical information, or financial information (other than when related to payment for our Services). Please do not provide this information to us through e-mails, feedback forms or in any other way.

**Using our Services**

We collect certain technical information to help us operate and provide our Services to you. This technical information includes standard web information about visits and system capabilities as you access and use the Services, such as:

  * Information about the device(s) you use to access our Services, including MAC address, IP address, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, device type, and device identifiers;
  * Information about your visits to the Websites, including the full URL clickstream to, through and from the Websites (including date and time);
  * Information we need and use to facilitate your use of our Services (including to provide access to third party websites and services), such as URL requests, destination IP addresses, or device configuration details; and
  * Pages you view or search for, page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), your engagement with certain variable/dynamic elements of a page and methods used to browse away from the page.

We also collect information using cookies and web beacons (see  **Cookies& Web Beacons **below).

**Other Collection of Information**

Our Services may also, from time to time, contain links to and from social media platforms. You may choose to connect to us through a social media platform and when you do, and to the extent available, we may collect additional information from you, such as your screen names, profile picture, contact information, contact list, and the profile pictures of your contacts, through the social media platform. Please be advised that social media platforms may also collect information from you. We do not have control over the collection, use and sharing practices of social media platforms and encourage you to review their usage and disclosure policies and practices, including the data security practices, before using the social media platforms.

We may supplement the technical information we collect from you with information collected by third parties. Third parties may include advertising partners or other providers that help us understand our users and provide better service to our users.

On occasion, we may combine data collected from other third party sources and add it to the information you or your company or organization has provided. We may also compile your contact data from other sources to contact you if we think you or the company you represent would be interested in our Services.

Third parties unaffiliated with us may also collect information about you, including tracking your browsing history, when you use our Services. We do not have control over these third party collection practices and advise you to adjust the settings of your browsers or install plug-ins and add-ins if you wish to minimize these third party collections.

_**How Your Information May Be Used**_

We may use any information we collect to:

  * Allow us to operate our Services, including administration, internal operations, troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;
  * Manage your access to our Services;
  * Send you information that allows you to use our Services;
  * Contact you directly about your use of an account or Service for which you are registered;
  * Create reports for customers that may include both aggregate trends and the organizations that are viewing their releases;
  * Comply with laws and regulations;
  * Carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including billing and collection;
  * Notify you about changes to our Services;
  * Allow you to participate in interactive features of our Services;
  * Fulfill our obligations to our customers in our provision of Services to them;
  * Protect the integrity and maintain the security of our Services, including secured areas of our Websites;
  * In any other way that we describe when you provide the information; and
  * For any other purpose with your consent.

In some cases, how we treat and use information will depend on the type of information. Some of the information we collect through your use of our Services or communications with us, such as your name, work address, phone number, e-mail address, billing information associated with your account, and/or the name of the company, individual or organization on behalf of which you are authorized to use the Services may personally identify you. We will treat this information as “Personally Identifiable Information.” We will also treat as Personally Identifiable Information any non-identifiable information that is combined with Personally Identifiable Information.

We may use your information, including Personally Identifiable Information, to:

  * Respond to your requests, feedback or questions;
  * Provide you with information about products or services, from us or third parties, that may interest you;
  * Send you e-mails about updates, information, or alerts regarding our Services.

We may use Technical Information or non-Personally Identifiable Information to:

  * Evaluate and improve our Services and present content in the best way for you and for your device(s);
  * Serve advertisements on or through our Services;
  * Measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and other customers like you, and to deliver relevant advertising to you and other customers like you.

We may also combine technical information or non-Personally Identifiable Information about your use of our Services with similar information that we obtain from other users to use in an aggregate or anonymous manner for similar purposes.

_**How Your information May Be Shared**_

We will not sell your Personally Identifiable Information or share your Personally Identifiable Information with third parties for the third party's own direct marketing purposes. Please note that if you click on or otherwise interact with an advertisement through our Services, however, the advertiser may assume that you meet its target criteria, even though we have not shared your Personally Identifiable Information.

We may share information, including Personally Identifiable Information, with our service providers and agents to the extent reasonably necessary to provide our Services to you. For example, we use a third party platform for e-mail and cannot communicate with you without disclosing your e-mail address to our third party e-mail provider. These third parties use any information we share only to support us and our efforts to provide our Services.

We may share any information, including Personally Identifiable Information with:

  * Our subsidiaries and affiliates
  * Our service providers and sub-contractors to the extent reasonably necessary to enable us provide our Services;
  * A buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution or other sale or transfer of some or all of our assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation or similar proceeding, in which Personally Identifiable Information held by us about our users is among the assets transferred;
  * A third party with whom we must legally share information about you;
  * You, upon your request;
  * The company or organization you represent upon their request;
  * Other third parties with your express consent.

We may also disclose your Personally Identifiable Information:

  * To comply with any court order, law or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request;
  * To investigate potential unauthorized access or misuse of our Services or otherwise enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements;
  * To protect our assets or rights, including for billing and collection purposes;
  * If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of PR Newswire, our customers or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.
  * For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information.

We may share non-Personally Identifiable Information, aggregate or anonymous data:

  * With analytics, search engine, or other service providers that help us improve our Services;
  * To advertisers and advertising networks to select and serve relevant advertisement.

In the event that we receive a request from a governmental entity to provide it with your Personally Identifiable Information, we will take reasonable attempts to notify you of such request, to the extent reasonably possible and legally permissible.

_**Cookies & Web Beacons**_

We may use cookies, beacons and similar technologies, now or in the future, to support the functionality of our Services. This provides a better experience when you visit our Websites and allows us to improve our Services.

  * Browser Cookies. A browser cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. That cookie then communicates with servers, ours or those of other companies that we authorize to collect data for us, and allows recognition of your personal computer. We associate cookies with Personally Identifiable Information only if you use the automatic recognition capabilities on restricted areas of the Websites, order a Service, use the personalization services available as part of the Websites, or ask us to contact you with additional marketing information. Otherwise, we do not collect Personally Identifiable Information from browser cookies and we do not associate browser cookies with your Personally Identifiable Information.   
You may use the tools available on your computer or other device to set your browser to refuse or disable all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. However, if you refuse or disable all browser cookies, you may be unable to access certain parts of our Websites or use certain features or functionality of our Services.   
You may choose whether to activate automatic recognition when you register for a Service, or after registration, you may disable the persistent cookie that supports recognition using the tools in your browser. If you choose to disable the cookies that support automatic recognition, you will need to re-enter your user ID and password each time you access a gated portion of the website.   
Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it refuses all cookies, we may issue cookies when you direct your browser to use our Services. 
  * Flash Cookies. Certain features of our Services may use local stored objects called flash cookies to collect and store information about your preferences and navigation to, from and on our Websites. We also include cookies in our third party hosted video players to count the number of unique viewers who see a customer’s video press release and to provide aggregate reporting. The cookies do not identify you as an individual or track your online behavior. We do not collect Personally Identifiable Information from flash cookies and we will not associate them with your Personally Identifiable Information.   
Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings as are used for browser cookies. To learn how you can manage your Flash cookie settings, visit the Flash player settings page on Adobe's website. If you disable or refuse Flash cookies, please note that some parts of our Services may be inaccessible or may not function properly.

  * Web Beacons. Our Websites and e-mails may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear GIFs, pixel tags and single-pixel GIFs) that permit us to, for example, count users who have visited those pages or opened an e-mail and for other website-related statistics. Web beacons in e-mail marketing campaigns allow us to track your responses and your interests in our content, offerings and web pages. You may use the tools in your device to disable these technologies as well.

****_**Your Choices**_  
You may have the opportunity to receive certain communications from us related to our Services. If you provide us with your e-mail address in order to receive communications, you can opt out at any time by following the instructions at the bottom of our marketing e-mails, including e-mails that are sent through our Services. Please note that certain e-mails may be necessary for the operation of our Services. You will continue to receive these e-mails, if appropriate, even if you unsubscribe from our optional communications.

Certain websites you visit may provide options regarding advertisements you receive. For more information or to opt out of certain online behavioral advertising, please visit [http://www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

Some browsers support a “Do Not Track” feature, which is intended to be a signal to websites that you do not wish to be tracked across different websites you visit. Our Services do not currently change the way they operate based upon detection of a Do Not Track or similar signal.

Please note that we cannot control how third party websites or online services you visit through our Services respond to Do Not Track signals. Check the privacy policies of those third parties for information on their privacy practices.

You may opt out of our direct telemarketing contacts by requesting us to remove you from our direct telemarking list. Please note that opting out from our direct telemarketing contacts does not limit us from contacting you for other purposes, including those contacts that are reasonably necessary to provide you with our Services. If you decide to opt out of our direct telemarketing contacts, allow a reasonable time for us to process your request and do not hesitate to contact us at privacy@PRNewswire.com if you encounter any problems with your request. The FTC also maintain a National Do Not Call Registry at [www.donotcall.gov/register/reg.aspx](http://www.donotcall.gov/register/reg.aspx). By registering your number with the FTC may also limit our direct marketing contacts to that number.

Journalists and others who use ProfNetsm Experts may choose not to disclose their identity when in direct communication with experts and company information officers by following the directions on that website to "cloak" their identity.

We value the accuracy of the information we have about you. Journalists, registered users, customers, experts and resources may update their information at any time by following directions available on the registration page for the applicable Service. Otherwise, to review or correct your Personally Identifiable Information, please contact us at privacy@PRNewswire.com. 

_**Securing Your Information**_

The security of your information is important to PR Newswire, and we have established reasonable administrative, technical, and physical safeguards designed to protect Personally Identifiable Information against theft or misuse. Unfortunately, no system can guarantee complete security of your information. As a result, while we strive to protect your information from unauthorized third parties, PR Newswire cannot ensure or warrant the security of your information, including your Personally Identifiable Information. Thus, your use of the Services and communication with us about them is at your own risk.

You are responsible for protecting your username(s) and password(s) and for the security of information that you transmit to us over the internet. 

_**Children** _

Our Services are directed to working professionals. Our Services are not intended for children under 13 years of age, and we do not knowingly collect information from children under 13. If you are under 13 years of age, you are not permitted to submit any personally identifiable information to us. 

_**Links to Third Party Sites** _

Our Services may contain links to third party websites and services, including those of our partner networks and advertisers. Please note that these websites and services may have their own privacy policies. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the policies of any third parties. If you chose to access any websites or services linked from our Services, please check the applicable policies before you use or submit any personal data to such website or service.

This Privacy Policy applies to PR Newswire's Services only. While our Services may contain links to third party websites and services, we are not responsible or liable for the content or privacy policies of such third parties. 

_**Interpretation** _

Your use of our Services may be governed by our Terms of Use located at <http://www.prnewswire.com/terms-of-use-apply.html>, and the terms of service at <http://www.prnewswire.com/customer-terms-conditions-landing-page.html> and/or other agreements. In the event that the provisions of any such agreements differ from or conflict with the provisions of this Privacy Policy, the Service-specific terms will apply. 

_**Changes to Our Privacy Policy** _

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time to align with changes to our business practices and/or changes to our legal requirements. We will post the updated Privacy Policy on this page (at <http://www.prnewswire.com/privacy-policy.html>), and will indicate that the updates have been made by changing the effective date first written above. We urge you to check back periodically to check whether there have been updates to our Privacy Policy.

Your continued use of the Services or communication with us about the Services after the updated Privacy Policy has been posted (or any other indication of your consent) will constitute your acceptance of the updated Privacy Policy.

Please note that we may condition your continued access to our Services on your consent to changes to this Privacy Policy. 

_**Contact** _

If you have questions, comments or requests relating to this Privacy Policy, please e-mail us at privacy@prnewswire.com, or write to us at: 

Privacy Requests   
PR Newswire Association LLC   
350 Hudson Street   
New York, New York 10014
